Guide to the Kent State Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional material, 1979 -1990; Accession 1991-M-004
  - Correspondence and subject files
    - Correspondence, general (Box 1)
    - Crank mail (Box 1)
    - Davies, Peter (Box 1)
    - Dept. of the Interior (Box 1)
    - Dick Cavett Show, public response to (Box 1)
    - Engdahl, David E. (Box 1)
    - Gordon, Bill (Box 1)
    - Holstein, Elaine B. Miller (Box 1)
    - Jeff Miller Memorial Award, John F. Kennedy Senior High School (Box 1)
    - Keane, Paul (Box 1)
    - Kelner, Joseph (Box 1)
    - Kendall/Hunt Publishing Co. (Box 1)
    - "Kent State," NBC docu-drama (Box 1)
    - Elaine Holstein's response to NBC docu-drama, "Kent State," John F. Kennedy High School (Box 1)
    - "Kent State: A Wake," Occidental College (Box 1)
    - Kent State addresses and telephone numbers (Box 1)
    - Kent: State: Annual (11th) Commemoration Program (Box 1)
    - Kent State: "May 4th Speech," by Elaine Holstein on the 15th anniversary of KSU shootings (Box 1)
    - Kent State: "Anniversary," by Elaine Holstein on the 18th anniversary of KSU shootings (Box 1)
    - Kent State: 20th Anniversary (Box 1)
    - Kent State civil suit settlement: statement by students wounded and by parents of students killed at KSU (Box 1)
    - Kent State Families Meeting (Box 1)
    - Kent State Memorial (Box 1)
    - Kent State Newsletter (Box 1)
    - "The Kent State Story," Police Chief (Box 1)
    - Kent State University (Box 1)
    - Kent State University May 4, 1970 Memorial Design Competition (Box 1)
    - "Kent State University's Petition to the White House: Ten Months of Deceit, " Bill Gordon (Box 1)
    - Mann, Halton (Box 1)
    - Miller, Russ (Box 1)
    - Mitchell, John N., Office of the Attorney General (Box 1)
    - Plainview-Old Bethpage Public Library (Box 1)
    - Press and TV people, correspondence of (Box 1)
    - The Progressive, Inc. (Box 1)
    - Retrial correspondence (Box 1)
    - Rhodes, James (Box 1)
    - Richardson, Elliott: "An open letter to the new Attorney General of the U.S.," from Elaine Holstein (Box 1)
    - School of the Martyrs of Kent, "Martires de Kent," Cuba (Box 1)
    - Segal, George: sculpture of "Abraham and Isaac" in memory of May 4, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Shaker Heights High School, Ohio (Box 1)
    - "Shoot the Bastards," interviews (Box 1)
    - U.S. Senate (Box 1)
    - U.S. Supreme Court decision (Box 1)
    - "Where Does It End?" poem by Jeff Miller (Box 1)
    - The White House (Box 1)
    - Whitcoulls Limited (Box 1)
    - Woolverton, William H., Jr. (Box 1)
    - Writings by others (Box 1)
  - Financial records: trial costs, travel, etc.
  - Photographs
  - Printed material
  - Miscellaneous
  - Legal papers: Correspondence, briefs, appeals, motions, depositions, and trial proceedings (Box 2)
  - Clippings (5 folders) (Box 3)
- Additional material, 1967-1989; Accession 1994-M-010
  Received from Mary Vincent, 1989.
  - Correspondence and subject files
    - Center for Peaceful Change, 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Chronology of Events, 1970 April-1976 May (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Keane, Paul: articles by or about, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Keane, Paul: "Kent State: A Ten Year Ministry", 1980 March (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "Kent State F.A.C.T.", 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Loose notes and unidentified photograph, 1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Magazine articles, 1970-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - May 4 Coalition, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - May 4 Memorial Services, 1973, 1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - May 4 Resource Center, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - May 4 Task Force, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Michener, James: book reviews of his work, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "Ohio Civil Liberties", 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Printed material, writings pertaining to Kent State, 1970-1979, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Books
    - Casale, O., ed.: The Kent Affair, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Michener, J. A.: Kent State, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Stone, I. F.: Killings at Kent State, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Daily Kent Stater
    - 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - FYI, 1970 October 26 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Inside Kent State, 1985 May 6, 1986 April 14 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Additional material, 1975-1977; Accession 1994-M-090
  Received from Loring Mandel, 1994.
  - Summation by chief counsel, Joseph Kelner, for the plaintiffs, Kent State University Trial, civil suit, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - United States Court of Appeals, 6th Circuit, Krause v. Rhodes: brief for appellants, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - United States Court of Appeals, 6th Circuit, Krause v. Rhodes v. Davies: appendix of movant-appellant Peter Davies, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Additional material, 1970-1978; Accession 1998-M-076
  Received from Sanford Rosen, 1998.
  Sanford Rosen, one of the lawyers for the families of Kent State shooting victims, petitioned under the Freedom of Information Act to have materials released pertaining to the United States Department of Justice, Civil Rights Division's investigation of the Kent State killings. The materials released comprise this accession and are arranged in the order in which they were received.
  - Case related correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Citizen correspondence
    - 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Incoming correspondence, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5 - 9)
  - Pleadings, undated
    - Index (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1-18 (Box 1, Folder 11 - 28)
  - Press conferences/press releases, 1970-1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970, 1973-1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 30 - 31)
  - Intra-agency memos
    - [includes index], 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Citizen and official correspondence
    - 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 34 - 46)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 47 - 56)
    - 1970-1976 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - 1971-1976 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Additional material, Circa 1970-2008; Accession 2006-M-115
  Received from Paul Keane, 2007.
  See also Series II. Paul Keane Papers and Accessions 1982-M-016 and 1990-M-047.
  - "Kent State: A Ten Year Ministry", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Contains Keane's reminiscences and numerous photocopies of material from his journals and diaries relating to the May 4, 1970, shootings at Kent State University.
  - Typed and unedited transcription of Keane's journals relating to the Kent State shootings, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Reflections on 'The University and the Community of Learning,'" and text of the speech by Henry Steele Commager on which it is based, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Commager's speech was given at Kent State University on 10 Apr 1971. Keane's reflections are printed from a web site.
- Additional material, 1970-2017; 1970-1971; Accession 2015-M-067; .13; 10 boxes
  Gift of Paul Keane, 2015 AND 2017.
  The materials are open for research.
  - "Whiting-Out History," Paul Keane's reflection on the forty-fifth anniversary of the Kent State shootings on May 4, 1970, 2015 (Box 1)
    General
    Includes typescript, published version from White River Junction's Valley News, 2015 April 26, and e-mail correspondence relating to the article.
  - "Are Flowers Better Than Bullets?", 2017 April 6 (Box 1)
  - Audiorecordings, 1970-1971
    - Kansas State University, 1970 May 4 (Box 2)
    - Nixon's Cambodia, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Nixon; Cambodia, 1970 October 4 (Box 3)
    - Washington, 1970 October 16 (Box 4)
    - Kent, Ohio, federal grand jury, 1971 October 10 (Box 5)
    - Concerning petitions: includes Wright-Board of Elections, Sindell, Gonef-Registrar, Jim Bruss, Dr. Bigelow, and Robin Grimmin, 1971 October 11 (Box 6)
    - Confusion around Ziegler's statements, phone conversation with reporter, Ziegler's secretary, Jerry Warren, 1971 November (Box 7)
    - Discussion with newsmen and press coverage, Circa 1970 (Box 8)
      Only about 15 minutes taped.
    - Unidentified female voice, Circa 1970 (Box 9)
    - Unidentified, Circa 1970 (Box 10)
- Additional material, 1972-2016; Accession 2017-M-0005
  This accession consists of material on the Doonesbury comic strip about the events at Kent State University and the controversy that accompanied the publication of the strip. Materials include a scanned image of the comic by Garry Trudeau attached to a draft of a page from Kent State: A Ten Year Ministry, a scanned image of the November 6, 1972 article on the controversy from the Akron Beacon Journal, and a printout of the online copy of an article written by Paul Keane titled "Forum: One man's role in '72 Doonesbury flap," published in the New Haven Register. Materials are dated to 1972 and 2016.
  - Materials on the Doonesbury comic strip controversy, 1972-2016-07-24 (Box 1, Folder 1)